<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>HTTP on khuencheng's Personal Blog</title><link>https://khuencheng.github.io/tags/http/</link><description>Recent content in HTTP on khuencheng's Personal Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 23:11:34 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khuencheng.github.io/tags/http/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Streamlining Real-Time Data: Master HTML5 SSE like ChatGPT</title><link>https://khuencheng.github.io/posts/html5-sse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 23:11:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://khuencheng.github.io/posts/html5-sse/</guid><description>Introduction In the age of real-time interactivity where services like ChatGPT excel, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial for developers to leverage technologies that allow for seamless data streaming in their applications. This article will delve into the world of HTML5 Server-Sent Events (SSE), a powerful tool akin to the technology behind conversational AI interfaces. Similar to how ChatGPT streams data to provide instant responses, SSE enables web browsers to receive updates from a server without the need for repetitive client-side requests. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re building a chat application, a live notification system, or any service requiring real-time data flow, this guide will equip you with the knowledge to implement SSE efficiently in your applications, ensuring a responsive and engaging user experience.
Understanding Server-Sent Events (SSE) Server-Sent Events (SSE) is a web technology that facilitates the server&amp;rsquo;s ability to send real-time updates to clients over an established HTTP connection. Clients can receive a continuous data stream or messages via the EventSource JavaScript API, which is incorporated in the HTML5 specification by WHATWG. The official media type for SSE is text/event-stream.
Here is an illustrative example of a typical SSE response:
event:message data:The Current Time Is 2023-12-30 23:00:21 event:message data:The Current Time Is 2023-12-30 23:00:31 event:message data:The Current Time Is 2023-12-30 23:00:41 event:message data:The Current Time Is 2023-12-30 23:00:51 Fields in SSE Messages Messages transmitted via SSE may contain the following fields:</description></item></channel></rss>